<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://vaithak.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://vaithak.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-20T22:48:32+05:30</updated><id>https://vaithak.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Vaibhav’s blog</title><author><name>Vaibhav Thakkar</name><email>vaibhav.thakkar.22.12.99@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">First post</title><link href="https://vaithak.github.io/first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First post" /><published>2021-06-11T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2021-06-11T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://vaithak.github.io/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vaithak.github.io/first-post/">&lt;p&gt;Hello World :wave:
This is my first post on this blog and I really hope that it won’t be the last :sweat_smile:.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till now, I haven’t been very fond of writing big articles or essays, reasons of which are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am too lazy to write. As we know that our thoughts are significantly faster than our writing or typing speed, so I used to think that by writing down stuff, the thought process will slow down and it won’t benefit me in any way&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What changed ?&lt;/strong&gt;: My philosophy of why writing can be beneficial is that when we have ideas in our mind only, then we can only do a spatially-local traversal between them, i.e if we consider the ideas and thoughts as a large connected web, if we are currently thinking of an idea, then in our mind we can only visualize only a subset of it’s 1-hop or at max 2-hop neighbors, and the traverse the web in this way. But when we have written down our thoughts, we gain an extra ability to see our thoughts, this can help us in recognizing some features which many not be present in our thoughts. This can result in visualizing a very large neighborhood and even entire paths of ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I thought that I have nothing to share, why will anyone be interested in reading my posts?&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What changed ?&lt;/strong&gt;: I realized that there is always something to share, even if the same material exists somewhere else, but still, a new perspective can always make a difference (hopefully a positive one).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have (very) bad writing skills (is this a reason or a consequence :thinking:)&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What changed ?&lt;/strong&gt;: Absolutely nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-now&quot;&gt;Why now?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn’t that I realized all the above reasons now, I have known them for a good amount of time, but in the wise words of Joker “All it takes is a little push”.&lt;br /&gt;
It came after my selection in &lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/projects/#6649856422051840&quot;&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/a&gt;, the mentors in the GeomScale organization encouraged all of the selected students to write a blog explaining the work progress. So, here I am trying to write one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, my aim of writing this post is so that I can revisit it after 1-2 years when I would have written a good number of posts. and see what has changed since then.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vaibhav Thakkar</name><email>vaibhav.thakkar.22.12.99@gmail.com</email></author><category term="first-post" /><summary type="html">Hello World :wave: This is my first post on this blog and I really hope that it won’t be the last :sweat_smile:.</summary></entry></feed>